This is the last one.
（料理人Ａ）最後の品です
（薙切(なきり)えりな）うん
Disgusting!
（えりな）まずいっ！
（料理人Ａ）ううっ
（料理人Ａ）
あーちゃー
あちゃちゃちゃちゃー！
Ow!
It's incredible that you lot have managed to come up with this many train wrecks.
まったく
そろいもそろって よくもここまで
ひどい品を並べられたものね
That last oyster gruel, in particular,
特に最後のカキ雑炊
was as if... yes,
そう まるで―
as if I were taking a bath with a western lowland gorilla!
ニシローランドゴリラと
混浴しているような味がするのよ
Again, we have no idea what you mean.
Family: Hominidae; Genus: Gorilla;
Western Lowland Gorilla
The largest living primate.
Eats primarily fruit, grass, leaves, and vines.
The fur on the back of adult males turn
greyish-white, hence the name "silverbacks."
One male forms a harem with several females...
（料理人Ｂ）またしても難解な…
Her palate is incomparable to that of a mere mortal.
（料理人Ｃ）
やはり凡人とは
ひと味違う感性をお持ちだ
I can tell that you omitted one of the steps in prep work.
察するに 下ごしらえの段取りを
１つ省いたようね
I am aware that your restaurant group is expanding,
（えりな）
あなたのグループが
事業拡大に入ったことも―
and that you're trying to increase your efficiency for that reason.
そのための効率化を
進めていることも知っています
But how dare you presume that gives you the right to defile my tongue with such garbage?
だからと言って こんな品で
私の舌を汚(けが)すことが―
許されると思って？
ひ… ひいい… も… も…
M-My apologies, Lady Erina!
（料理人たち）
申し訳ありませんでした
えりなお嬢様ー！
Nakiri
（幸平創真(ゆきひらそうま)）あ…
It's time for you to go, Souma.
（幸平城一郎(ゆきひらじょういちろう)）
旅立つ時だ 創真
Go figure out what you've got.
（城一郎）
てめえの器を測ってこい
God Tongue
I stick out like a sore thumb.
（創真）場違い感が
とんでもねえぞ
Why do all the other applicants have butlers and guards and stuff?
他の受験生みんな なんで執事とか
護衛がついてんだ？
Oh, I didn't tell you?
Dad
Cell
（城一郎）
あれ？　言ってなかったっけ
You're taking the transfer admission exam
for one of the best culinary academies in the country.
お前が編入試験を受ける そこは
日本屈指の料理学校
The graduation rate is less than 10 percent.
卒業到達率10％以下の
超絶エリート校だぜ
It's a super-elite institution.
Educational Institution
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Best of luck with that, Souma.
Educational Institution
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
（城一郎）まあ 頑張れよ 創真
そこの学校で…
Educational Institution
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
At that school—
Educational Institution
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
（マクフリー･マクラクラン）
ヘーイ ジョー！
Educational Institution
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Hey, Jo!
Educational Institution
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Please wait a moment!
（城一郎）
プリーズ･ウェイト･
ア･モーメント！
親父 今どこにいるんだ？
Where are you right now, Dad?
（城一郎）
ニューヨークシティ
New York City.
In the Manhattan Royal Hotel's reception hall for VIPs.
マンハッタン･ロイヤル･ホテル
ＶＩＰ専用
レセプションホール
今そこで飯作ってんだ
That's where I'm cooking now.
Hey, Jo!
ヘーイ ジョー！
I'm so happy you came back to New York!
よくぞニューヨークに
帰ってきてくれた
This is the best dinner ever!
最高のディナーだ
ハハハハハ…
大声出すんじゃねえよ
ドクター･マクフリー
Simmer down, Dr. McFly!
また血圧 上がるぜ
Your blood pressure will go up again!
Delicious.
うまい！
ああ…
病を得て議会から離れた この身
After taking a medical leave of absence from Congress,
（元議員）
最後に幸平氏の料理を食べられたら
もう悔いはないと思っていたが―
I resigned myself to my fate and thought my life would be complete
if I could eat Yukihira's cooking just one last time.
But this only makes me greedy for more!
まだ何度でも食べたいと
欲張ってしまうな　ハハハハ…
Let's come again, sir!
（秘書Ａ）先生 また来ましょう
Yes, as many times as possible!
（秘書Ｂ）ええ 何度でも
（女性）ああっ
（僧正）幸平は ここかぁ！
Is Yukihira here?!
Please come back, Master!
（僧侶Ａ）
お戻りください 僧正様！
We're in the middle of a fast!
（僧侶Ｂ）
断食の最中にございますぞ
門徒たちに示しが…
What example are you setting—
ええい　黙れ 黙れ 黙れ！
Bah, silence, silence, silence!
You're telling me to spurn Yukihira's cooking
when it's right in front of me?!
幸平の料理を目の前にして
食ってはならぬだと？
ならば 私は信仰を捨てる～！
In that case...
I reject my calling!
（僧侶たち）僧正様～！
Master!
（僧正）幸平～！
Yukihira!
（城一郎）
最初はインド
イタリア スペインと仕事して―
First I went to India, then Italy and Spain.
I just arrived in America yesterday.
昨日 アメリカに入ったんだ
The plan is for me to be cooking up and down the East Coast for a while.
しばらくは東海岸の都市で
料理を出す予定になってる
Huh?
（創真）
はあ？
話についていけねえんすけど
I don't understand.
Well, let's just say someone called in a favor.
（城一郎）
ま ちょいと頼まれてな
Hey, Souma.
なあ 創真よ
その学園で 卒業まで
生き残れないようじゃ―
If you can't survive that academy,
you can kiss your pipe dream
of surpassing me goodbye.
俺を超えるなんて笑い話だな
（創真）やってやらあ！
Just watch me!
Good.
よし　じゃあ 特別に
料理が上達する秘けつを教え…
Then let me tell you the secret to improving your—
He hung up on me.
もう切りやがった
Where did you go, Yukihira?!
（僧正）幸平 どこだ～！
Coming!
はいよ！
（城一郎）いいか 創真
Listen up, Souma.
The trick to becoming a good chef is...
いい料理人になるコツは―
Yukihira
自分の料理の全てを
ささげたいと思えるような―
finding a woman you want to cook for
for the rest of your life.
Yukihira
そんな女と出会うことだぜ
So what's next on my plate?
（えりな）で 次の予定は？
This, Milady.
（新戸(あらと)緋沙子(ひさこ)）こちらです
Judging transfer exams?
（えりな）編入試験の審査？
So this is the kind of boring work I get for joining the council.
評議会入りすると
こんな仕事も回ってくるのね
着替えを済ませたら
向かいます
I'll head over after I change.
Damn it...
クソッ　何が笑い話だ
A pipe dream? Yeah, right.
I'll definitely make it to graduation, damn it!
ぜってー 生き残って
やろうじゃねえかよ！
S-Sorry!
あ ごめん　蹴っちまった
I didn't notice you sitting there.
No need to apologize.
（二階堂圭明(にかいどうよしあき)）気にしないで
君も編入希望なんだね
You also wish to transfer in, right?
Take a seat, won't you?
（二階堂）まあ 座りなよ
（創真）おう
High school qualifying exam results are being announced for Tohtsuki's junior high school,
（二階堂）今日は遠月(とおつき)中等部からの
進級試験結果発表と―
and exams are being held for people like us hoping to transfer in,
僕らのような他の中学からの
編入受験もあるから―
so it's pretty lively today.
にぎやかだね
I'm Nikaido Yoshiaki.
僕は二階堂圭明
My family runs a French restaurant.
家はフランス料理店を
やっている
Oh, what a coincidence.
（創真）へえー 奇遇だなあ
俺の実家も料理屋なんだよ
Mine runs a restaurant too.
That may not be such a coincidence.
奇遇でもないかもよ
The man over there is the heir
to a national restaurant chain,
（二階堂）
向こうにいる彼は
全国展開してるレストランの跡取り
and that one's family runs a wholesale seafood business that supplies the entire Kanto region.
あっちは関東中に鮮魚を卸してる
大問屋の息子
Almost everyone here has
some sort of tie to the culinary world.
ここにいる ほとんどの者が
料理業界のサラブレッドなのさ
Oh?
ふ～ん
What's the name of your place?
君の家は 何ていう店？
It's called Yukihira.
ああ “ゆきひら”っていう
ゆきひら…
Yukihira...
You serve traditional fare, perhaps?
料亭さんかな？
アッハハ
そんな大した店じゃねえよ
No way, it's nothing that fancy.
We're a diner downtown.
下町にある
定食屋なんだけどさ…
（創真）がはっ！
How dare you sit next to me,
低俗な庶民が―
you low-class commoner!
この僕と並んで座るなあ～！
Listen up!
（二階堂）いいか よく聞け
This academy isn't for the likes of you!
この学園は
庶民の来ていい場所じゃない
It is a sacred grove, an institution of learning for
denizens of the upper echelons of the food industry!
食の上流階級に生きる者だけが
学ぶことを許される聖なる庭
That's the kind of place Tohtsuki Teahouse Culinary Academy is!
（二階堂）それがここ
遠月茶寮(とおつきさりょう)料理学園！
A low-born like you won't even make it
past the screening of applications.
お前のような低俗な民は
書類審査だけで落とされるだろ…
Huh?
ゆきひらで食ったこともねえくせに
うちの格を決めんじゃねえ！
You haven't even tried Yukihara's food!
You don't get to pass judgment!
Young Master!
（執事たち）坊ちゃーん！
Look, someone from a diner thinks he can attend this academy.
（受験生Ａ）
見ろよ　定食屋のせがれが
編入するつもりらしいぜ
（受験生Ｂ）
ハッ　冗談だろ
身の程知らずにも限度があるぞ
You've got to be kidding me.
He should know his place.
This isn't giving me high hopes for this place.
（創真）
先が思いやられるぜ
If this is how things are right off the bat,
のっけから この調子じゃ―
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
who knows what sort of pompous ass
I'll get as the examiner.
審査するのは
どんな偉そうな奴なんだ
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Transfer Examination Hall
High School Division
Tohtsuki Culinary Academy
Hey, is that...
（受験生Ｃ）
あれって ひょっとして…
Y-Yeah.
Greetings, transfer applicants.
編入希望の皆さん
I am Nakiri Erina, and I have been
assigned to judge today's transfer exam.
本日の編入試験を
一任されました―
Nakiri Erina (15)
Middle School, 3rd Year
薙切えりなと申します
A girl?
（創真）女の子？
しかも学園の制服 着てる
And she's wearing the school's uniform.
（創真）あの子が審査員なのか？
She's the examiner?
What do the instructions from the exam department say?
（えりな）
入試課から通達は？
I'll read it now.
（緋沙子）読み上げます
Examinees will first undergo interviews in groups of ten based on their applications.
まず申込書類を基に
10人単位で集団面接
They will then complete a practical,
in which they will cook up to three dishes.
そのあと３品ほど調理の実技
通過者をさらに…
Those who pass will—
Hmph.
（えりな）フン
（緋沙子）え？
What a waste of time.
くだらない
I have an idea.
そうね　調理台をここへ！
Bring a kitchen work table here.
（受験生たちのざわめき）
（緋沙子）あ… あ はい！
Y-Yes, Milady!
Cooking ingredients?
（受験生Ｅ）食材？
（受験生Ｆ）どうするんだ？
What's she up to?
The main ingredient will be eggs.
（えりな）メインの食材は卵
一品 作りなさい
Make one dish.
私の舌をうならせた者にだけ
遠月学園への編入を許可します
Only those whose creations impress my palate will be allowed to transfer into this academy.
C'mon.
Furthermore,
（えりな）なお 希望者には
今から１分間だけ―
anyone who wishes to withdraw
his application has one minute to do so.
受験を取りやめ―
棄権することを認めましょう
What? One minute?
ええ？　１分？
あ… 棄権…
I'm withdrawing!
What?!
Hey, wait!
（創真）おい 待て！
（二階堂）ひい！
Why are you all running?!
何で逃げんだよ
You don't know who she is?!
お前 まさか
あのお方を知らないのか？
Huh? Nope.
あ？　知らん　教えて
Who is she?
Nakiri Erina has the finest palate known to mankind! A divine tongue!
（二階堂）薙切えりなは
人類最高の“神の舌”
The God Tongue!
“ゴッドタン”の持ち主！
Huh?
Humans typically begin talking
between the ages of one and two.
（二階堂）
赤ちゃんが言葉を話し始めるのは
普通 １歳から２歳の間だが―
彼女は生後３カ月の時
初めて しゃべった言葉が…
But her first spoken words, at three months old, were...
（えりな）まずっ
ぷはっ　コクが足りない
Not enough depth of flavor.
Given the small glimpse of her genius already present at birth,
（二階堂）
生まれてすぐに その才能の
片鱗(へんりん)を見せた彼女は―
幼少時から 日本中の有名店の
味見役を依頼されてきた
she has been asked to be the taste tester at famous restaurants across the nation since she was young.
All the heavyweights in the food world are her clients!
料理界の重鎮たちは皆
薙切えりなの顧客なんだ
Any evaluation she makes will spread far and wide in the industry!
彼女が下した評価は
業界全体に知れ渡る！
If she...
（二階堂）
もしも… もしも彼女に―
If she were to brand you as an talentless imbecile,
才能なしの
烙印(らくいん)を押されでもしたら―
your career in the food world would be over!
料理人としての人生が
閉ざされてしまうんだよぉ～！
I figured most of them were hopeless incompetents.
（えりな）やっぱり
見込みのないグズばかりね
I can't be bothered to waste my time on such fools.
あんな連中のために
私の時間を割くわけにはいかないわ
もう今日の予定は
消化しましたね
I believe that clears my schedule for the day?
（緋沙子）あ… はい
Uh, yes.
I will be testing new dishes in my private quarters.
これから私室で
新作料理を試します
えりな様の新作料理…
Erina-sama's new dishes...
What's the matter, Hisako?
どうしたの 緋沙子
物欲しそうな顔をして
It looks like you wish to ask me something.
Oh, no, well...
いえ… その…　ああ…
Would you like the privilege of trying my cooking?
私の料理を試食する権利が
欲しいの？
I... I would!
ほ… 欲しい… です
まあ 卑しい子だこと
What a shameless hussy you are.
Oh, please forgive me!
ううっ…
も… 申し訳ありません
First we'll have to report that no one passed.
その前に報告しなくてはね
合格者はゼロだと
Yes.
はい…
Hey, so are there no other restrictions on the dish?
あのさあ
作る料理は 何でもいいの？
What?
何？
I...
（えりな）私に… 挑む者が…
have a challenger?
Mama!
Sob, sob
Uh, uh...
As long as you use eggs,
卵さえ使用していれば
作る品は自由よ
you can make anything you want.
But are you sure about this?
でも本当に やる気？
辞退するなら今のう…
This is your last chance to—
Man, I was so worried!
いやあ　ホント焦ったわ～
I thought you might fail me
before I even got to cook!
料理もしねえで落とされたら
どうしようって思ってさぁ
How dare you!
離れろ！　この方を
どなたと心得る！
Do you know who she is?!
Who is she?
（創真）誰なの？
She's the top of her junior high class
（緋沙子）
中等部主席生徒にして―
and the youngest member
ever of the Elite Ten Council,
学園の最高意思決定機関
遠月十傑(じゅっけつ)評議会の―
the highest decision-making body in the academy:
史上最年少メンバー
薙切えりな様だ
Nakiri Erina-sama!
Whoa.
（創真）おお～ こりゃ
なかなかの業物(わざもの)ですねぇ
What a magnificent knife.
Don't wander off!
（えりな･緋沙子）
ウロウロするな！
Huh?
Let me ask you one last time.
もう一度 聞くわよ
本当に私の試験を受ける気なの？
Are you really going to take my exam?
Huh?
え？　だって―
But...
I just have to get you to say it tastes good, right?
うまいって言わせれば
いいんだろ
Of course I'll take the test.
受けるよ もちろん
This boy...
こいつ…
Erina-sama.
えりな様
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Souma.
（えりな）幸平創真
Yukihira Souma
実家は定食屋
His family runs a diner.
It's clear that he's a second-rate cook.
見るからに二流の料理人
私の高貴さが分からないのね
He has no conception of my noble pedigree,
just like a stray dog would have no idea of a gemstone's value.
（えりな）野良犬に宝石の価値が
分からないように
ウフッ
If that's your attitude,
そこまで言うなら
味わって差し上げるわ
I'll taste your food.
The food of the bottom feeders of the culinary world.
（えりな）
料理業界底辺の味をね
Then I'll be happy to...
喜んで うちの店の
とっておきを出してやるよ
serve you...
our specialty!
Hang onto your seat,
お待ちを 薙切試験官殿
Examiner Nakiri!
Eggs are a fundamental ingredient
卵は和洋中 あらゆるジャンルの
基本となる食材
in Japanese, Western, and Chinese cuisine across all culinary genres.
Erina-sama tastes egg-based haute cuisine every day.
（緋沙子）
日々 様々な高級卵料理を口にする
えりな様に対して―
一体どんな料理を…
What will he serve her?
I see that he's using beaten eggs,
卵は溶いて使うようだけど―
but I have no idea what dish he's working towards.
完成形が
全く見えてこないわね
Yukihira Souma-kun, what are you making?
（えりな）
幸平創真君 作る品は一体 何？
Huh?
You still can't tell at this stage?
ここまで見て まだ分かんねえの？
プププッ
今すぐ不合格にするわよ！
Do you want me to fail you right now?!
Listen!
いいこと？　不出来な者を
相手にしている暇はないの
I don't have time to waste on ill-conceived food.
I'm asking you if you have any intention of
making a dish that is suitable for my palate!
この私の舌に見合う料理を―
作るつもりがあるのかって
聞いてるのよ
Fine, I'll tell you.
いいぜ　教えてやる
（創真）
俺の作る料理は
食事処(どころ)ゆきひら 裏メニューその８
What I'm making is the eighth item on Yukihira Diner's secret menu!
Secret menu?
（えりな）
裏メニューですって？
一体どんな手の込んだ料理を…
And what manner of elaborate dish would this be?
Rice with seasoning!
ふりかけごはん
Huh?
Cut the crap!
ふざけないで！
I knew you were a good-for-nothing cook.
やっぱり底辺の料理人ね
とんだ時間の無駄だったわ
What a waste of time.
Erina-sama...
（緋沙子）えりな様
（創真）もちろん
ただのふりかけじゃねえよ
It goes without saying that
it's no ordinary seasoning.
What I'm making...
俺が作るのは―
is rice with transforming seasoning!
“化けるふりかけごはん”だ
Transforming seasoning?
化けるふりかけですって？
All right!
（創真）
さあ そろそろ上がりますよ
Almost done!
Yukihira Souma...
幸平創真
What dish is he about to serve?
この男 一体どんな品を
出すつもりなの？
（創真）おまちどお！
Thank you for waiting!
No.
いや―
Like I initially thought, he's just messing with me!
やっぱり バカにしてる！
えっへへ
It really is ordinary.
（緋沙子）ほんっとに
ただのふりかけだ
In the end, it's still the work of a second-rate cook.
しょせん二流料理人の仕事ね
全く食指が動かないわ
It fails to arouse my appetite.
My palate has been called the God Tongue.
（えりな）
神の舌とまで呼ばれる味覚を持つ
私の食卓には―
Only the most elaborate and refined
haute cuisine graces my dining table.
贅(ぜい)と趣向を凝らした
高級品だけが並ぶ
Indeed, I reside in a gourmet paradise!
まさに美食の天上界
How dare he serve something like this to me?
そこで生きてきた私に
こんな物を出すなんて
This examination is over.
（えりな）
試験は これで終了です
Erina-sama!
（緋沙子）えりな様！
この品の本当の姿は
これからなのに
But you haven't seen its true form yet.
What do you mean?
どういう意味かしら
There's something hidden beneath the egg.
（えりな）卵の陰に何か…
Well, keep your eyes peeled.
まあ 見てなよ
ふりかけの真価は
白米の上でこそでしょ
The true value of a rice seasoning
is only revealed when it's served on rice.
Well, then...
さて…
Here we go!
（創真）仕上げだ
It's melting... from the rice's heat?
（えりな）ご飯の熱で溶けて…
And as it melts, it coats the egg.
溶けると同時に
卵が次々とコーティングされていく
What is this aroma?
この香りは… 鶏
Chicken?
The fragrant, mellow aroma of gently simmered chicken is wafting through the air.
（えりな）
じっくり煮込まれた鶏肉の
まろやかな香りが立ち上ってくる
So this is rice with transforming seasoning?
これが 化けるふりかけごはん
It looks completely different from before.
さっきまでとは
見栄えが まるで違う
I wonder what it tastes like.
一体どんな味がするのか
I suppose I can deign to take one bite.
ひと口だけ
味見して差し上げます
Hand it over!
さっさと器をよこしなさい
Here you go!
おあがりよ
（えりな）はむ…
I can't believe this!
私としたことが！
審査を忘れて味わってしまった
I forgot to judge it and just savored the taste?!
What was that texture?!
今の食感は… 何？
Oh?
（創真）あれえ？
You're going for a second bite?
ふた口目 いっちゃうの？
I thought I heard you say one bite only.
ひと口だけって
聞いた気がするけど？
Do you have any complaints about that?!
何か文句ありますかぁ？
（えりな）えいっ えいっ…
（創真）冗談だってば
I'm just kidding.
Take your time and eat up.
（創真）ゆっくり食いな
It's aspic, isn't it?
煮こごりね
Bingo!
大正解！
四角いのは手羽先の煮こごりだ
The cubes are aspic made from chicken wingtips.
Aspic is formed when meat or fish broth
with high gelatin content congeals into jelly.
（創真）煮こごりってのは
ゼラチン質の多い肉や―
魚の煮汁が冷えて
ゼリー状に凝固したものだけど―
I simmered chicken wingtips with bonito stock, sake, and light soy sauce,
手羽先をかつおだし 酒
薄口しょうゆで煮込んで―
then finely chopped the aspic
once it cooled and solidified.
その煮汁を冷やして 固めて
細かく切ったんだ
When that's sprinkled over hot rice,
（創真）
熱々ご飯に ふりかければ
溶け出した手羽先の煮汁が―
the aspic melts and the gelatinous broth coats the egg soboro.
卵そぼろにプルンと絡みつく
In effect, this aspic is a rich soup infused with the umami of chicken.
（えりな）言うなれば
この煮こごりは―
鶏肉のうまみが溶け込んだ
濃厚なスープ
The rich flavor and saltiness of this broth...
とろりとした煮汁の
コクと塩っけが―
are enhancing the fluffy egg
soboro's subtle sweetness.
ふわふわっの卵そぼろの
優しい甘さを引き立てている
With every bite, the fluffy and gelatinous textures caress the insides of your mouth.
そして噛(か)む度に
ふわふわと とろとろが―
口の中をなで回していく
The melted aspic elevates the egg
to entirely new heights.
溶けた煮こごりが 卵のおいしさを
格段に跳ね上げているんだわ
This is unlike any dish I've ever eaten.
これは 今まで食べてきた
どの料理にも似ていない
It's an entirely new world of flavor.
私の知らなかった味の世界
どうよ どうよ
食わずに帰らねえで よかったろ？
So how is it?
Good thing you didn't storm off earlier, right?
S...
（えりな）だ… 黙りなさい！
（創真）お？
Silence!
まだ審査は途中よ！
The evaluation has yet to be concluded!
Even if the menu item is humble in the extreme,
こんな ありふれたメニューでも
創意工夫で逸品に化けさせる
we use our creativity to transform it into a masterpiece!
That is Yukihira cooking.
（創真）
これが ゆきひらの料理だ
Even so...
（えりな）だけど―
how can I, a denizen of gourmet paradise, accept this?
美食の天上界に生きる この私が
認めるわけには…
This, a dish by the personification of all things déclassé!
（えりな）
こんな庶民代表のような男が
作った料理なんか…
I can't... accept this.
（えりな）認める… わけには…
I just... can't.
認める… わけ… には…
This flavor...
この味は まるで…
It's as if...
I'm being caressed by angel feathers!
（えりな）
天使の羽根で
愛撫(あいぶ)されているかのような…
Go away!
（えりな）あっち行けえ！
Stay away!
（えりな）
来ないでえ！　来ないでよぉ！
Stay away, I say!
No!
（えりな）いやああん！
I don't want to accept it.
（えりな）認めたくない！
but my palate... my body can't help but react.
舌が 体が 反応しちゃう！
Sure, we may be a small diner,
（創真）
確かに うちは
ちっこい定食屋だし―
and I'm sure you're one of the elites of the culinary world.
あんたが食の上流階級なのも
本当なんだろうね
But, you know,
けどさ 上座に
ふんぞり返ってるだけじゃ―
I bet there are some things you can't make
if you get too comfortable sneering down at people from your throne.
作れねえものもあるぜ
きっと
Erina-sama.
えりな様…
Well? What is it?
（創真）さあ どうだい？
Yukihira-style rice with seasoning.
（創真）
ゆきひら流ふりかけごはん
Is it delicious or disgusting?
うまいか まずいか言ってみな
Tell me!
It's...
disgusting!
まずいわよ！
（創真）あれえええ！
What?!
（えりな）何よ 何よ 何よ！
How dare he, how dare he, how dare he?!
Talking down to me like that!
あんな偉そうな物言い！
To me, Nakiri Erina!
この薙切えりなに対して！
Unforgivable!
許せない！
くうぅぅぅ…
Ow
Yukihira Souma...
（えりな）幸平創真…
（創真）へらへらへらへら…
（えりな）君のような人間は―
Tohtsuki Academy has no need for people like you!
遠月学園には
必要ありません！
Hello? It's Erina.
（えりな）もしもし えりなです
Please tell Grandfather,
おじいさまに…
学園総帥にお伝えください
the director of the academy,
that no one passed the exam today.
本日の編入試験 合格者は―
ゼロ名です
Fail
Yukihira Souma
End
Next Episode
Next time on Shokugeki no Souma,
the third dish:
Menu
That Chef  Never Smiles
That Chef Never Smiles.
Please enjoy.
M
a
s
t
e
r
!
M
a
s
t
e
r
!
M
a
s
t
e
r
!
（薙切仙左衛門(なきりせんざえもん)）フッ
フン！
（えりな）次回「食戟(しょくげき)のソーマ」
３品目をどうぞ
「その料理人は
笑わない」
ご機嫌よう